Register of the Charls E. Walker Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1954-1997.
  - Press conference, Treasury Building, Washington, D.C., 1969 August 1 (Folder 14: 5)
  - Interview, ABC's Issues and Answers, 1969 August 17 (Folder 14: 6)
  - Press conference briefing, Department of the Treasury, Washington, D.C., 1969 September 3 (Folder 14: 7)
  - Remarks before the American Bankers Association, Ninth Annual Convention, Honolulu, Hawaii, 1969 September 30 (Folder 14: 8)
  - News conference, St. Louis, Missouri, 1969 October 22 (Folder 14: 9)
  - Speech, The American Life Convention, St. Louis, Missouri, 1969 October 22 (Folder 14: 10)
  - News conference, Argus Research Conference, Phoenix, Arizona, 1969 November 22 (Folder 14: 11)
  - Remarks, Omaha Chamber of Commerce, Omaha, Nebraska, 1970 January 13. (Folder 14: 12)
    Also includes news conference
  - Remarks, State of Iowa Volunteers, Des Moines, Iowa, 1970 January 14. (Folder 14: 13)
  - Interview, Sunday in Chicago, WMAQ-TV, Chicago, 1970 February 13 (Folder 14: 14)
  - Appearance, Sixty Minutes, 1970 February 17 (Folder 14: 15)
  - Interview, Five Interviews with Isabelle O'Donnell, WAVA Radio, 1970 February 23 (Folder 14: 16)
  - "Cost-Push Inflation: What It Is and What Not to Do About It," remarks before the National Industrial Conference Board, Financial Conference, New York, 1970 February 27. (Folder 14: 17)
    Also includes press interview
  - Press briefing, Seminar of Western Independent Bankers Association, San Francisco, California, 1970 March 9 (Folder 14: 18)
  - "Government's Anti-Inflationary Policy Debated," interview, The Today Show, 1970 March 13. (Folder 14: 19)
    Typescript transcript
  - Remarks, Tenth Annual Washington Conference on Business-Government Relations, 1970 March 23 (Folder 14: 20)
  - Remarks, Treasury Safety Council, 1970 May 4 (Folder 14: 21)
  - Address and press conference, National Association of Supervisors of State Banks, Boston, Massachusetts, 1970 May 6 (Folder 14: 22)
  - Commencement address, Ashland College, Ashland, Ohio, 1970 June 7. (Folder 14: 23)
  - Press conference, Dallas, Texas, 1970 June 10 (Folder 14: 24)
  - Speech, Dallas, Texas, 1970 June 10 (Folder 14: 25)
  - Remarks, Commission on Financial Structure and Regulation, 1970 June 27 (Folder 14: 26)
  - Remarks, Union League Club, 1970 July 1 (Folder 14: 27)
  - Remarks, Tax Section of the American Bar Association, St. Louis, Missouri, 1970 August 9 (Folder 14: 28)
  - Speech, National Association of Business Economists, Boston, Massachusetts, 1970 September 15 (Folder 14: 29)
  - "To Combat Inflation: What Congress Must Do," speech published in November issue of Reader's Digest, 1970 October (Folder 14: 30)
  - Address, 43 rd Annual Convention of the National Bankers Association, St. Louis, Missouri, 1970 October 16 (Box-folder 15: 1)
  - Remarks, Pepperdine College, Los Angeles, California, 1970 October 22 (Folder 15: 2)
  - Remarks, Seventeenth Annual Bankers' Forum, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1970 October 30 (Folder 15: 3)
  - "Telling It Like It Really Is," press conference, Washington, D.C., 1970 October 31 (Folder 15: 4)
  - Address, Joint Council on Economic Education, New York, New York, 1970 November 6 (Folder 15: 5)
  - Remarks, United States Savings and Loan League Annual Convention, 1970 November 10 (Folder 15: 6)
  - Remarks, Acapulco, Mexico, 1970 November 19 (Folder 15: 7)
  - Address, National Housing Center, Council of the National Association of Home Builders, Houston, Texas, 1971 January 18 (Folder 15: 8)
  - "Take Stock in America," remarks, Top Management Campaign, New York, New York, 1971 February 11 (Folder 15: 9)
  - Statement, Board of Governors of the Inter-American Development Bank, Buenos Aires, Argentina, 1971 March 1 (Folder 15: 10)
  - Interview with Larry King, WTVJ TV, Miami, Florida, 1971 March 26 (Folder 15: 11)
  - "Social Goals and the Market Economy," University of Texas, 1971 April 14 (Folder 15: 12)
  - Remarks, Fifty-Fourth Annual Meeting of the Chamber of Commerce of Greenwich, Greenwich, Connecticut, 1971 April 26 (Folder 15: 13)
  - Remarks, Twelth Annual Meeting of the Board of Governors of the Inter-American Development Bank, Lima, Peru, 1971 May 11 (Folder 15: 14)
  - Remarks, Federal Government Accountants Association's Twentieth Annual Symposium, Washington, D.C., 1971 June 28 (Folder 15: 15)
  - "Quick Frozen Economy," broadcast, Educational Broadcasting Corporation, 1971 August 19 (Folder 15: 16)
  - "Revenue Sharing Is Not Dead," Public Works Congress and Equipment Show, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1971 September 12 (Folder 15: 17)
  - "What's the Issue?" interview for the Chamber of Commerce of the United States Mutual Broadcasting System, 1971 October 7 (Folder 15: 18)
  - Remarks, 44th Annual Convention of the National Bankers Association, 1971 October 8 (Folder 15: 19)
  - Statement on the Administration's program to increase deposits in minority banks, 1971 October 26 (Folder 15: 20)
  - Opening remarks, U.S. Department of Labor, 1971 November 4 (Folder 15: 21)
  - Excerpts from remarks, National Association of Manufacturers, 1971 December 3 (Folder 15: 22)
  - "Your Senator's Report," interview, radio and television broadcast, 1971 December 20 (Folder 15: 23)
  - Remarks, American National Cattlemen's Association, Denver, Colorado, 1972 January 20 (Folder 15: 24)
  - Statement, American Management Association, New York, New York, 1972 February 4 (Folder 15: 25)
  - "Domestic Economic Policy in the United States," Vienna, Austria, 1972 April 19 (Folder 15: 26)
  - Remarks, Board of Governors of the Asian Development Bank, Vienna, Austria, 1972 April 21 (Folder 15: 27)
  - Remarks, Senior Management Seminar of the National Bankers Association, Atlanta, Georgia, 1972 July 21 (Folder 15: 28)
  - Excerpts of remarks, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, 1972 July 24 (Folder 15: 29)
  - Remarks, Downtown Jaycees and Kiwanis Club, Washington, D.C., 1972 September 7 (Folder 15: 30)
  - Excerpts of remarks, Seminar for Business and Finance Editors, Wharton School of Finance, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1972 September 12 (Folder 15: 31)
  - Remarks, CBS Radio, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1972 September 12 (Folder 15: 32)
  - Remarks (with Arthur Okun) at Bankers Audio Forum, 1972 October. (Folder 15: 33)
  - Speech, "Taxation: Myths and Realities," 98th Annual Convention of the American Bankers Association, Dallas, Texas, 1972 October 10 (Folder 15: 34)
  - Panelist, "Nixon vs. McGovern: Does It Make Any Difference Economically?" The Everett McKinley Dirksen Republican Forum, 1972 October 11 (Folder 15: 35)
  - Excerpts of remarks, Regional Council Conference, San Francisco, California, 1972 November 3 (Folder 15: 36)
  - Interview, WETA TV, Washington, D.C., 1972 November 6 (Folder 15: 37)
  - Excerpts of remarks, Regional Council Conference, Dallas, Texas, 1972 November 29 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Excerpts of remarks, Securities Industry Association, Boca Raton, Florida, 1972 November 30 (Folder 16: 2)
  - Interview, Bankers Monthly Magazine, Washington, D.C., 1972 December 14 (Folder 16: 3)
  - Commentary on Nightly Business Report, WPBT/Miami, Florida, American Council for Capital Formation, 1982 May 31 - 1986 September 29 (Folder 16: 4-5)
  - "Why the President Should Support a Commission on Spending and Taxes," 1983 October 20 (Folder 16: 6)
  - "Briefing Book for Ways and Means Retreat," 1993 February 10 (Folder 16: 7)
  - "Clintonomics in 1995-1996: Talking Points," 1994 July 18 (Folder 16: 8)
  - "Administration Tax Policy in 1995," 1994 October 17 (Folder 16: 9)
  - "Pro-Growth Tax and Trade Policies in the 104th Congress," 1994 November 28 (Folder 16: 10)
- WRITINGS BY OTHERS, 1954-1972.
  Includes some correspondence
  - General (Folder 16: 11)
  - Adams, Sherman (Folder 16: 12)
  - Anderson, Clay (Folder 16: 13)
  - Anderson, Robert (Folder 16: 14)
  - Ashton, James (Folder 16: 15)
  - Atkinson, Thomas (Folder 16: 16)
  - Baird, Julian (Folder 16: 17)
  - Balderston, C. Candy (Folder 16: 18)
  - Bober, W. C. (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Boeschenstein, Harold (Folder 17: 2)
  - Bopp, Karl (Folder 17: 3-4)
  - Bronfenbrenner, M. (Folder 17: 5)
  - Brozen, Yale (Folder 17: 6)
  - Byrd, James (Folder 17: 7)
  - Chandler, Lester (Folder 17: 8)
  - Cox, Bert (Folder 17: 9)
  - Daane, J. Dewey (Folder 17: 10)
  - Dauer, Ernst (Folder 17: 11)
  - De Block, Leo (Folder 17: 12)
  - Du Vall, Kenneth (Folder 17: 13)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Folder 17: 14)
  - Fand, David (Folder 17: 15)
  - Fleming, Lamar (Folder 17: 16)
  - Friedman, Milton (Folder 17: 17-18)
  - Friedman, Milton (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Gilbert, R. R. (Folder 18: 2)
  - Griffith, John (Folder 18: 3)
  - Grove, David (Folder 18: 4)
  - Hauge, Gabriel (Folder 18: 5)
  - Hust, Hurley, G. (Folder 18: 6)
  - Irons, Watrous (Folder 18: 7)
  - Jacobs, Walter (Folder 18: 8)
  - Johnson, Norris (Folder 18: 9)
  - Johnson, Thomas (Folder 18: 10)
  - Kemp, Arthur (Folder 18: 11)
  - Larmour, M. W. (Folder 18: 12)
  - Levin, Bertram (Folder 18: 13)
  - Linger, Irving (Folder 18: 14)
  - Loewy, Harris (Folder 18: 15)
  - Luckett, Dudley (Folder 18: 16)
  - Machlup, Fritz (Folder 18: 17)
  - Martin, William (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - McCracken, Paul (Folder 19: 2)
  - McDonald, Stephen (Folder 19: 3)
  - Mills, A. L. (Folder 19: 4)
  - Morton, Walter (Folder 19: 5)
  - Nowell, R. I. (Folder 19: 6)
  - O'Leary, James (Folder 19: 7)
  - Patman, Wright (Folder 19: 8)
  - Prochnow, Herbert (Folder 19: 9)
  - Pruit, Wilford (Folder 19: 10)
  - Raisty, L. B. (Folder 19: 11)
  - Ray, D. T. (Folder 19: 12)
  - Reierson, Roy (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Reuss, Henry (Folder 20: 2)
  - Riefler, Winfield (Folder 20: 3)
  - Robertson, J. L. (Folder 20: 4)
  - Robertson, Willis (Folder 20: 5)
  - Roose, Robert (Folder 20: 6)
  - Sachs, Alexander (Folder 20: 7)
  - Schiff, Frank (Folder 20: 8)
  - Schlesinger, James (Folder 20: 9)
  - Scott, Ira (Folder 20: 10)
  - Scribner, Fred (Folder 20: 11)
  - Seiden, Martin (Folder 20: 12)
  - Shirk, Stanley (Folder 20: 13)
  - Shultz, George (Folder 20: 14)
  - Smith, Robert (Folder 20: 15)
  - Smutny, Rudolf (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Solomon, Robert (Folder 21: 2)
  - Sprinkel, Beryl (Folder 21: 3)
  - Stark, W. R. (Folder 21: 4)
  - Szymczak, Matt (Folder 21: 5)
  - Thomas, Woodlief (Folder 21: 6)
  - Van Cleave, Robert (Folder 21: 7)
  - Waugh, Frederick (Folder 21: 8)
  - Whittlesey, Charles R. (Folder 21: 9)
  - Williams, John (Folder 21: 10)
  - Wooten, Ben H. (Folder 21: 11)
  - Young, Ralph (Folder 21: 12)
  - Zook, Paul (Folder 21: 13)
- BANKING FILE, 1951-1980
  - General (Folder 21: 14)
  - American Bankers Association (Folder 21: 15-16)
  - Automation (Folder 21: 17)
  - Bank liquidity (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Banking statistics (Folder 22: 2)
  - Bank stocks as investments (Folder 22: 3)
  - Bank structure (Folder 22: 4)
  - Central Banking Seminars (Folder 22: 5)
  - Commercial banks
    - General (Folder 22: 6-7)
    - Research activities (Folder 22: 8)
    - Texas (Folder 22: 9)
  - Credit policy (Folder 22: 10)
  - Federal Reserve Banks
    - General
      - Federal Reserve policies (Folder 22: 11)
      - Federal Reserve policies (Box-folder 23: 1-2)
      - Federal Reserve System (Folder 23: 3-5)
      - Post war changes in structure of member banks (Folder 23: 6)
      - Price stabilization (Folder 23: 7)
      - Recirculation of Federal Reserve, 1954 (Folder 23: 8)
      - Redemption of treasury bonds (Folder 23: 9)
      - Repurchase (Folder 23: 10)
      - Reserve requirements (Folder 23: 11-12)
    - Eleventh Federal Reserve District (Folder 23: 13)
    - Federal Reserve Bank of Dallas (Box 24)
      - General (Folder 24: 1-2)
      - Participation in "Operation Alert 1957" (Folder 24: 3)
      - Responses to Committee on Legislation of the Conference of Presidents of the Federal Reserve Banks. Subcommittee on Legislation (Folder 24: 4-8)
      - Survey of municipal bond issues (Folder 25: 1)
      - Treasury stabilization fund (Folder 25: 2)
  - International banking and finance
    - General (Folder 25: 3-4)
    - Bank of England (Folder 25: 5)
  - Republic National Bank of Dallas (Folder 25: 6)
  - Savings and Loan Associations (Folder 25: 7)
- OFFICE FILE OF THE UNITED STATES DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY, 1961-1972
  - Briefings for new officials (Folder 25: 8)
  - Memoranda
    - General (Folder 25: 9)
    - Anderson, Robert (Folder 25: 10)
    - Baird, Julian (Folder 25: 11)
  - Reports (Folder 25: 12)
  - Statements (Box 26)
    - Treasury officials (Folder 26: 1-5)
    - Treasury Secretary, Robert Anderson (Folder 26: 6-7)
  - Speeches and writings
    - General, including by Secretary Robert Anderson and Under-Secretary Fred Scribner (Folder 26: 8)
    - Anderson, Robert (Box-folder 27: 1-3)
  - Subject file
    - Bonds
      - General (Folder 27: 4-7)
      - U.S. Treasury Department Savings Bonds Conference, 1960. (Folder 27: 8-9)
        Correspondence, memoranda, speeches
    - Budget, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 28: 1-2)
    - Joint Economic Committee
      - General (Folder 28: 3)
      - Hearings (Folder 28: 4)
    - Taxation (Folder 28: 5)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1954-1980.
  Includes catalogs, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and reports
  - Advance refunding (Folder 28: 6)
  - American Finance Association (Folder 28: 7-11)
  - American Finance Association (Box-folder 29: 1-4)
  - Balance of payments (Folder 29: 5-7)
  - Business cycles (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Business forecasts (Folder 30: 2)
  - Carter, Jimmy (Folder 30: 3)
  - Committee for Economic Development (Folder 30: 4-6)
  - Committee on the Present Danger (Folder 30: 7-9)
  - Debt ceiling (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Debt management (Folder 31: 2-8)
  - Debt and Tax Rate Extension Act of 1960 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Economic growth
    - General (Folder 32: 2)
    - Debt management (Folder 32: 3)
    - Finance (Folder 32: 4)
    - Nixon Committee (Folder 32: 5)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D. Press releases and statements (Folder 32: 6)
  - Gold reserves (Folder 32: 7)
  - Gold standard (Folder 32: 8)
  - Housing (Folder 32: 9)
  - Inflation (Folder 32: 10-11)
  - Interest rates (Box 33)
    - General (Folder 33: 1-4)
    - Interest rate ceiling (Folder 33: 5-8)
    - Interest rate for individuals (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Investment funds (Folder 34: 2)
  - Monetary policy (Folder 34: 3-4)
  - Money supply (Folder 34: 5)
  - Open market (Folder 34: 6-7)
  - Presidents – United States – Election – 1960 (Folder 34: 8-11)
  - Savings bonds (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - Shultz, George (Folder 35: 2)
  - Southwestern Social Science Association (Folder 35: 3)
  - Task Force on Federal Tax Policy. (Folder 35: 4-7)
    Correspondence and reports
  - Taxation (Folder 35: 8)
  - United States. Congress - Democratic study groups, 1960 (Folder 35: 9-10)
  - United States. Congress - Democratic study groups, 1960 (Box-folder 36: 1)
- PRINTED MATTER, 1954-1965
  - Articles on economics (Folder 36: 2)
  - Catalogs of books on economics (Folder 36: 3)
  - Clippings (Folder 36: 4-5)
  - Official publications, United States. Congress (Folder 36: 6)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1982 (Box 37)
  - 3 prints of unidentified group, n.d. (Folder 37: 1)
  - 1 print of Julian Baird, n.d. (Folder 37: 2)
  - 1 print of Ronald Reagan and 1 print of James Brady, 1983 (Folder 37: 3)